<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pygrum</title>
    <link>https://pygrum.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pygrum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Pygrum</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 18:47:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pygrum.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Windows Portable Executable, Part 1 - PE Format</title>
      <link>https://pygrum.github.io/posts/understanding-windows-pe-1-pe-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 18:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pygrum.github.io/posts/understanding-windows-pe-1-pe-format/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This series aims to demonstrate how create tools based on your own research. To fully grasp how to work with Windows PEs, for use in malware development and analysis, we&amp;rsquo;re only using documentation from Microsoft. This approach helps me personally when it comes to developing new research, acquiring a well-rounded understanding of a topic, and improves my creativity. Hopefully it helps you too.&#xA;By the end of this article, we will have written a tool in C that extracts basic information from a given Windows PE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Disassembled Structs in IDA</title>
      <link>https://pygrum.github.io/posts/tackling-disassembled-structs-in-ida/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 23:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pygrum.github.io/posts/tackling-disassembled-structs-in-ida/</guid>
      <description>Reverse engineering software is a lot of work. Personally, the hardest part is figuring out which areas are worth examining further. Looking in the wrong places can cause you to miss valuable information.&#xA;One construct that can trip people up is struct representation in assembly. It can be unclear when a struct is being manipulated or accessed. After all, the struct is organised as a contiguous block of bytes, with each member residing sequentially in memory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pygrum.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://pygrum.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>This blog focuses on the deep technical aspects of cybersecurity. The topics covered are from both offensive and defensive sides of security, and prove useful to any security professional or enthusiast.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
